Would you let a company use your child to build an AI?
And if not, would you still refuse if it was required to go to school?
During the pandemic, many schools resorted to Microsoft Teams.
However, Microsoft Teams uses your data for "internal purposes", and what they exactly are, isn't specified.
So this could mean that your data is used for anonymous statistics,
but it could also mean that all your data is fed to an Azure Deep Learning Algorithm
to train on everything that you do.
This gave a dilemma to many parents.
They did want their child to go to school,
but they didn't want their child to be tracked by Microsoft.
As a result, they had to "consent" to Microsoft's trackers, because going to school is more important.
And there are many examples of this. For example:
a lot of university students had no choice but to agree to using proctoring software
even though it has a lot of privacy issues, security risks and discriminatory behaviours.
No-one should be able to force you to install any software on your computer.
You should be able to decide what you do and do not install.
That's called freedom of installation.
Support freedom of installation by reading more on the Digital Justice website.